<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Laba Gossip</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Laba Gossip</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://practicegithub2016.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>USBInterfaceOpen Fails to Open: Troubleshooting USB Communication with IOKit and Objective-C in macOS Environment</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230323/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230323/</guid><description>USBInterfaceOpen Fails to Open: Troubleshooting USB Communication with IOKit and Objective-C in macOS Environment If you encounter problems when using IOUSBInterfaceOpen to open a USB interface, there could be several reasons:
Permission issues: The application may not have sufficient permissions to access the USB device. Ensure that the application has the correct permissions. In some cases, you may need to run the application with root privileges.
Device occupied by another application: If the device is already opened and in use by another application, your application will not be able to open the interface.</description></item><item><title>Various Methods for Initializing Structures in C Language</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230322/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230322/</guid><description>Various Methods for Initializing Structures in C Language In C language, there are several ways to initialize structures. Here are a few methods.
Initialization using curly braces and a list: This is the most common method, using curly braces {} and providing a comma-separated list of values to initialize the members of the structure. The order of the values should correspond to the order of the members in the structure definition.</description></item><item><title>Initializing Structure Members to Zero in C Language</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230321/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230321/</guid><description>Initializing Structure Members to Zero in C Language In C language, to initialize the members of a structure to 0, you can use curly braces {} for initialization. The inside of the braces can be left empty, so the compiler will initialize all members of the structure to 0 (for numeric types) or a null character (for character types). For example:
#include &amp;lt;string.h&amp;gt; struct Student { char name[50]; int age; float score; }; int main() { struct Student student1 = {0}; // All members initialized to 0 or null character return 0; } Alternatively, you can use the memset function to set all members of the structure to 0:</description></item><item><title>USB Alternate Settings: Understanding Multi-Function Switching</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230305/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230305/</guid><description>USB Alternate Settings: Understanding Multi-Function Switching USB (Universal Serial Bus) is a widely-used communication standard for connecting various devices, such as keyboards, mice, cameras, printers, hard drives, and more. USB has multiple different configurations to support various functions and different types of data transfer.
Alternate Setting is an option within a specific interface of USB devices, allowing multiple functions to be supported by configuring different features or data endpoints within the same interface.</description></item><item><title>How to Get the Length of a File in C</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230304/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230304/</guid><description>How to Get the Length of a File in C. We can use the fseek() and ftell() functions from the standard library. Here is an example code that demonstrates how to get the length of a file:
FILE *file = fopen(&amp;#34;example.txt&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;r&amp;#34;); if (file == NULL) { printf(&amp;#34;Error opening file.\n&amp;#34;); return 1; } fseek(file, 0, SEEK_END); long size = ftell(file); fseek(file, 0, SEEK_SET); printf(&amp;#34;File size is %ld bytes.\n&amp;#34;, size); fclose(file); FILE *file = fopen(&amp;#34;example.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew vs MacPorts</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230303/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230303/</guid><description>Homebrew vs MacPorts Homebrew and MacPorts are both package managers for macOS, which means they are tools that allow you to easily install and manage software packages on your system. However, there are some differences between them that you should be aware of when deciding which one to use.
Homebrew is designed to be a lightweight, user-friendly package manager. It uses Git and Ruby to manage packages, and has a simple, command-line interface.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew vs MacPorts</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230302/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230302/</guid><description>Homebrew vs MacPorts Homebrew and MacPorts are both package managers for macOS, which means they are tools that allow you to easily install and manage software packages on your system. However, there are some differences between them that you should be aware of when deciding which one to use.
Homebrew is designed to be a lightweight, user-friendly package manager. It uses Git and Ruby to manage packages, and has a simple, command-line interface.</description></item><item><title>How to uninstall Homebrew completely</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230301/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230301/</guid><description>How to uninstall Homebrew completely To uninstall Homebrew completely from your macOS system, you can follow the steps below: Open the Terminal application.
Run the following command to uninstall Homebrew:
ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/uninstall)&amp;#34; This will remove Homebrew from your system.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew vs MacPorts</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230228/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230228/</guid><description>Homebrew vs MacPorts Homebrew and MacPorts are both package managers for macOS, which means they are tools that allow you to easily install and manage software packages on your system. However, there are some differences between them that you should be aware of when deciding which one to use.
Homebrew is designed to be a lightweight, user-friendly package manager. It uses Git and Ruby to manage packages, and has a simple, command-line interface.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Pages Hugo script</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230227/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230227/</guid><description>GitHub Pages Hugo script name: github pages on: push: branches: - main # Set a branch that will trigger a deployment pull_request: jobs: deploy: runs-on: ubuntu-22.04 steps: - uses: actions/checkout@v3 with: submodules: true # Fetch Hugo themes (true OR recursive) fetch-depth: 0 # Fetch all history for .GitInfo and .Lastmod - name: Setup Hugo uses: peaceiris/actions-hugo@v2 with: hugo-version: &amp;#39;latest&amp;#39; # extended: true - name: Build run: hugo --minify - name: Deploy uses: peaceiris/actions-gh-pages@v3 if: github.</description></item><item><title>brew error `initialize': Version value must be a string; got a NilClass ()</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230226/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230226/</guid><description>brew error `initialize&amp;rsquo;: Version value must be a string; got a NilClass () This error typically indicates that Homebrew&amp;rsquo;s version needs reinstall. To resolve this issue, you can follow these steps:
Open the Terminal application.
Run the following command to uninstall Homebrew:
ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/uninstall)&amp;#34; Run the following command to install Homebrew:
/usr/bin/ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)&amp;#34; Run the following command to check if Homebrew has been installed correctly:</description></item></channel></rss>