<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Laba Gossip</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Laba Gossip</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://practicegithub2016.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding QTextEdit in QT Programming</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231012/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231012/</guid><description>Understanding QTextEdit in QT Programming Introduction QTextEdit is a powerful widget in QT that provides a rich text editing functionality.
Common Functions of QTextEdit setText(): The setText() function allows you to set the text content of the QTextEdit widget. You can pass a QString as an argument to set the desired text. toPlainText(): The toPlainText() function returns the plain text content of the QTextEdit widget. It is particularly useful when you need to retrieve the text entered by the user.</description></item><item><title>Understanding QComboBox in QT Programming</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231011/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231011/</guid><description>Understanding QComboBox in QT Programming Introduction QComboBox is a powerful widget in QT programming that provides a dropdown list of items for users to choose from. It is highly customizable and allows developers to create interactive and user-friendly applications.
Creating a QComboBox To create a QComboBox in QT programming, we need to follow a few simple steps. First, we need to include the necessary header file:
#include &amp;lt;QComboBox&amp;gt; Next, we can create an instance of QComboBox using the following code:</description></item><item><title>Understanding QCheckBox in QT programming</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231010/</guid><description>Understanding QCheckBox in QT programming Introduction In QT programming, QCheckBox is a widget that allows users to select or deselect an option. It provides a checkbox that can be turned on or off, indicating the selection state. QCheckBox is a useful component in creating user-friendly interfaces and capturing user input.
Usage of QCheckBox QCheckBox provides several methods and signals to handle user interactions and retrieve the current state of the checkbox.</description></item><item><title>Common Methods of QPushButton in Qt.</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231009/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231009/</guid><description>Common Methods of QPushButton in Qt. Constructor:
You can create a QPushButton using different constructors, typically specifying the button&amp;rsquo;s text label and the parent window (parent widget) in the constructor. #include &amp;lt;QPushButton&amp;gt; QPushButton *button = new QPushButton(&amp;#34;Click Me&amp;#34;, parentWidget); Set Text Label (setText):
Use the setText method to set the text label displayed on the button. button-&amp;gt;setText(&amp;#34;New Label&amp;#34;); Set Icon (setIcon):
You can use the setIcon method to set an icon as the button&amp;rsquo;s image, enhancing its visual appeal.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with TCP Local Area Network (LAN) Communication in Qt</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231008/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231008/</guid><description>Getting Started with TCP Local Area Network (LAN) Communication in Qt When it comes to TCP LAN communication in Qt, it&amp;rsquo;s important to start with some fundamental concepts and steps:
Qt Networking Module: Qt provides a set of classes and modules for network communication, including QTcpSocket and QTcpServer, which allow you to easily create TCP client and server applications. Steps to Create a TCP LAN Communication: 1. Create a Qt Application First, create a Qt application.</description></item><item><title>Differences Between QDir::currentPath(), QCoreApplication::applicationDirPath(), and QCoreApplication::applicationFilePath() in Qt</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231007/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231007/</guid><description>Differences Between QDir::currentPath(), QCoreApplication::applicationDirPath(), and QCoreApplication::applicationFilePath() in Qt QDir::currentPath(): QDir::currentPath() returns the current working directory of the application. The working directory is the directory in which the application is running, typically the directory containing the executable file. This path can be either a relative or an absolute path, depending on where the application was launched from. QCoreApplication::applicationDirPath(): QCoreApplication::applicationDirPath() returns the directory containing the application&amp;rsquo;s executable file. This path represents the installation directory of the application, typically containing the application&amp;rsquo;s executable file and possibly other resource files.</description></item><item><title>QApplication vs. QCoreApplication in Qt</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231006/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231006/</guid><description>QApplication vs. QCoreApplication in Qt QApplication and QCoreApplication are both application classes in the Qt library, but they have some key differences:
Graphical User Interface (GUI) vs. Non-GUI Applications: QApplication is primarily used for creating GUI applications, providing initialization and functionality related to GUI, such as event loops and window management. QCoreApplication is used for creating non-GUI applications and serves as a more basic application class for tasks unrelated to events and GUI.</description></item><item><title>Common Ways to Use qDebug in Qt</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231005/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231005/</guid><description>Common Ways to Use qDebug in Qt Basic Output: Use the qDebug() function to directly output messages. For example:
You need to include the header file.
#include &amp;lt;QDebug&amp;gt; qDebug() &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;#34;This is a debug message&amp;#34;; Connect Multiple Values Using Stream Operator (&amp;laquo;): You can use the stream operator &amp;laquo; to connect multiple values and output them together to qDebug. For example:
int value = 123; QString message = &amp;#34;Hello, Qt!&amp;#34;; qDebug() &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;#34;Value:&amp;#34; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; value &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;#34;Message:&amp;#34; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; message; Specify Debug Message Type: You can use different overloaded functions of qDebug to specify different debug message types, such as qInfo, qWarning, and qCritical, which help differentiate messages of various levels.</description></item><item><title>Common Ways to Use QString in Qt</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231004/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231004/</guid><description>Common Ways to Use QString in Qt In Qt programming, QString is a commonly used string type that provides many useful methods for handling and manipulating string data. Here are some common methods of QString:
Constructors: You can create a QString using different constructors, including using string literals, C-strings, integers, and more.
QString str1 = &amp;#34;Hello, World!&amp;#34;; QString str2(&amp;#34;Another QString&amp;#34;); QString str3 = QString::number(42); // Converting an integer to QString Append and Concatenate: You can use append() or operator+ to append strings to the end of a QString.</description></item><item><title>Understanding rpath, runpath, and LD_LIBRARY_PATH</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231003/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231003/</guid><description>Understanding rpath, runpath, and LD_LIBRARY_PATH rpath (Runtime Path): rpath is a flag within an executable file used to specify the search path for shared libraries at runtime. When a program runs, the system searches for shared libraries based on the rpath setting. If the corresponding shared libraries are found, the program can run successfully. rpath is set during compilation or linking of the program and can be specified using the rpath option or in a Makefile.</description></item><item><title>Understanding QRadioButton in QT Programming</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231002/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20231002/</guid><description>Understanding QRadioButton in QT Programming QRadioButton is a class in QT programming that represents a radio button, which is a GUI element that allows users to select a single option from a set of mutually exclusive options.
To create a QRadioButton in QT, you can use the following code:
#include &amp;lt;QRadioButton&amp;gt; QRadioButton *radioButton = new QRadioButton(&amp;#34;Option 1&amp;#34;, this); radioButton-&amp;gt;setChecked(true); In the above code, we create a new QRadioButton object and set its text to &amp;ldquo;Option 1&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>How to Add Google AdSense Ads to Hugo's Ananke Theme</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230324/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230324/</guid><description>How to Add Google AdSense Ads to Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Ananke Theme To add Google AdSense ads to Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Ananke theme, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make edits to your theme files and insert ad code into your pages. Here are the step-by-step instructions:
Create a Google AdSense Account: If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a Google AdSense account, start by creating one on Google AdSense and set up your ad units.
Get Ad Code: Log in to your Google AdSense account, create ad units, and then get the ad code.</description></item><item><title>USBInterfaceOpen Fails to Open: Troubleshooting USB Communication with IOKit and Objective-C in macOS Environment</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230323/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230323/</guid><description>USBInterfaceOpen Fails to Open: Troubleshooting USB Communication with IOKit and Objective-C in macOS Environment If you encounter problems when using IOUSBInterfaceOpen to open a USB interface, there could be several reasons:
Permission issues: The application may not have sufficient permissions to access the USB device. Ensure that the application has the correct permissions. In some cases, you may need to run the application with root privileges.
Device occupied by another application: If the device is already opened and in use by another application, your application will not be able to open the interface.</description></item><item><title>Various Methods for Initializing Structures in C Language</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230322/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230322/</guid><description>Various Methods for Initializing Structures in C Language In C language, there are several ways to initialize structures. Here are a few methods.
Initialization using curly braces and a list: This is the most common method, using curly braces {} and providing a comma-separated list of values to initialize the members of the structure. The order of the values should correspond to the order of the members in the structure definition.</description></item><item><title>Initializing Structure Members to Zero in C Language</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230321/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230321/</guid><description>Initializing Structure Members to Zero in C Language In C language, to initialize the members of a structure to 0, you can use curly braces {} for initialization. The inside of the braces can be left empty, so the compiler will initialize all members of the structure to 0 (for numeric types) or a null character (for character types). For example:
#include &amp;lt;string.h&amp;gt; struct Student { char name[50]; int age; float score; }; int main() { struct Student student1 = {0}; // All members initialized to 0 or null character return 0; } Alternatively, you can use the memset function to set all members of the structure to 0:</description></item><item><title>USB Alternate Settings: Understanding Multi-Function Switching</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230305/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230305/</guid><description>USB Alternate Settings: Understanding Multi-Function Switching USB (Universal Serial Bus) is a widely-used communication standard for connecting various devices, such as keyboards, mice, cameras, printers, hard drives, and more. USB has multiple different configurations to support various functions and different types of data transfer.
Alternate Setting is an option within a specific interface of USB devices, allowing multiple functions to be supported by configuring different features or data endpoints within the same interface.</description></item><item><title>How to Get the Length of a File in C</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230304/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230304/</guid><description>How to Get the Length of a File in C. We can use the fseek() and ftell() functions from the standard library. Here is an example code that demonstrates how to get the length of a file:
FILE *file = fopen(&amp;#34;example.txt&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;r&amp;#34;); if (file == NULL) { printf(&amp;#34;Error opening file.\n&amp;#34;); return 1; } fseek(file, 0, SEEK_END); long size = ftell(file); fseek(file, 0, SEEK_SET); printf(&amp;#34;File size is %ld bytes.\n&amp;#34;, size); fclose(file); FILE *file = fopen(&amp;#34;example.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew vs MacPorts</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230303/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230303/</guid><description>Homebrew vs MacPorts Homebrew and MacPorts are both package managers for macOS, which means they are tools that allow you to easily install and manage software packages on your system. However, there are some differences between them that you should be aware of when deciding which one to use.
Homebrew is designed to be a lightweight, user-friendly package manager. It uses Git and Ruby to manage packages, and has a simple, command-line interface.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew vs MacPorts</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230302/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230302/</guid><description>Homebrew vs MacPorts Homebrew and MacPorts are both package managers for macOS, which means they are tools that allow you to easily install and manage software packages on your system. However, there are some differences between them that you should be aware of when deciding which one to use.
Homebrew is designed to be a lightweight, user-friendly package manager. It uses Git and Ruby to manage packages, and has a simple, command-line interface.</description></item><item><title>How to uninstall Homebrew completely</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230301/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230301/</guid><description>How to uninstall Homebrew completely To uninstall Homebrew completely from your macOS system, you can follow the steps below: Open the Terminal application.
Run the following command to uninstall Homebrew:
ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/uninstall)&amp;#34; This will remove Homebrew from your system.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew vs MacPorts</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230228/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230228/</guid><description>Homebrew vs MacPorts Homebrew and MacPorts are both package managers for macOS, which means they are tools that allow you to easily install and manage software packages on your system. However, there are some differences between them that you should be aware of when deciding which one to use.
Homebrew is designed to be a lightweight, user-friendly package manager. It uses Git and Ruby to manage packages, and has a simple, command-line interface.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Pages Hugo script</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230227/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230227/</guid><description>GitHub Pages Hugo script name: github pages on: push: branches: - main # Set a branch that will trigger a deployment pull_request: jobs: deploy: runs-on: ubuntu-22.04 steps: - uses: actions/checkout@v3 with: submodules: true # Fetch Hugo themes (true OR recursive) fetch-depth: 0 # Fetch all history for .GitInfo and .Lastmod - name: Setup Hugo uses: peaceiris/actions-hugo@v2 with: hugo-version: &amp;#39;latest&amp;#39; # extended: true - name: Build run: hugo --minify - name: Deploy uses: peaceiris/actions-gh-pages@v3 if: github.</description></item><item><title>brew error `initialize': Version value must be a string; got a NilClass ()</title><link>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230226/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://practicegithub2016.github.io/posts/20230226/</guid><description>brew error `initialize&amp;rsquo;: Version value must be a string; got a NilClass () This error typically indicates that Homebrew&amp;rsquo;s version needs reinstall. To resolve this issue, you can follow these steps:
Open the Terminal application.
Run the following command to uninstall Homebrew:
ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/uninstall)&amp;#34; Run the following command to install Homebrew:
/usr/bin/ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)&amp;#34; Run the following command to check if Homebrew has been installed correctly:</description></item></channel></rss>